      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-where">
        <title>Where should appear the action ?</title>
        <para>
          &nautilus; file-manager may display your custom action in different places,
          depending on you will request here, and if some item is currently selected.
        </para>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-selection">
          <title>Targeting the selection context menu</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in selection context menu</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; context menu, as long as at least one item is selected in 
            the file-manager. Your action will so deal with currently selected
            item(s).
          </para>
          <tip>
            <para>
              When an action targets the selection context menu, and is actually 
              displayed in &nautilus; context menu, then it is also displayed
              in the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu.
            </para>
          </tip>
          <para>
            This checkbox is activated by default.
          </para>
          <para>
            When targeting the selection context menu, and in order to be
            actually displayed, all the conditions defined in
            your candidate action must be met by each item currently selected
            in the &nautilus; file-manager. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-location">
          <title>Targeting the location context menu</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in location context menu</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; context menu, when the file-manager selection will be empty.
            Your action will so deal with currently displayed location.
          </para>
          <tip>
            <para>
              When an action targets the location context menu, and is actually 
              displayed in &nautilus; context menu, then it is also displayed
              in the <guimenu>File</guimenu> menu.
            </para>
          </tip>
          <para>
            When targeting the location context menu, and in order to be
            actually displayed, all the conditions defined in
            your candidate action must be met by the location currently displayed
            in the &nautilus; file-manager. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-toolbar">
          <title>Targeting the toolbar</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in the toolbar</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; toolbar.
          </para>
          <para>
            Actions displayed in the toolbar only deal with the location which
            is currently displayed in the file-manager, not with the items which
            may be currently selected (or not). In order to be displayed, all the
            conditions defined in your candidate action must so be met by the
            current location. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-notes">
          <title>Notes</title>
            <para>
              An action may target both the selection context menu, the location context
              menu and the toolbar, or one or more among these. If no target is defined,
              <abbrev>i.e.</abbrev> if the three checkboxes are unchecked, then your action
              will never be displayed.
            </para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-display">
        <title>How the action will it appear ?</title>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-display-menu">
          <title>If your action targets a menu</title>
          <para>
            Whether your action targets the selection context menu or the location
            context menu, and both in &nautilus; context menus that in 
            <guimenu>File</guimenu> or <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menus, your
            action will be displayed as
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Context label</guilabel> as a label,
              </para>
              <para>
                The label is a mandatory property of your action. If it happens
                to be empty, then your action will be considered as invalid by
                &prodname;, and will never be candidate to be displayed in the
                file-manager context menus.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Icon</guilabel>,
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                associated with the <guilabel>Tooltip</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>
              Depending of the exact configuration of your desktop environment,
              the icon may or may not be displayed in front of the label in
              the menu.
            </para>
          </note>
          <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the label, the icon name of the tooltip.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
          </tip>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-display-toolbar">
          <title>If your action targets the toolbar</title>
          <para>
            In the toolbar, your action will be displayed as
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Toolbar label</guilabel> as a label,
              </para>
              <tip>
                <para>
                  The toolbar label defaults to the same label than
                  those used in menus. By unchecking the
                  <guilabel>Use same label for icon in the toolbar</guilabel>
                  checkbox, then you can define a label specific to the
                  toolbar, usually shorter those defined for the menus.
                </para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Icon</guilabel>,
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                associated with the <guilabel>Tooltip</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>
              Depending of the exact configuration of your desktop environment,
              the toolbar label may or may not be displayed in front of the icon
              in the toolbar.
            </para>
          </note>
          <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the toolbar label, the icon name of the tooltip.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
          </tip>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-what">
        <title>What the action should it execute ?</title>
        <para>
          You most probably want your action eventually ends up with
          executing something. As a matter of fact, having something
          to execute is one of the few conditions which are required
          in order an action be considered as valid.
        </para>
        <para>
          Enter the command you wish to execute in the <guilabel>Path</guilabel>
          entry box. Or click on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to
          select a file on the filesystem.
        </para>
        <para>
          Enter the parameters of your command in the
          <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel> entry box.
        </para>
        <para>
          The <guibutton>Legend</guibutton> button has a toggling action:
          click once to display the <guilabel>Parameter Legend</guilabel>
          dialog box; click a second time to hide it.
        </para>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-legend">
            <title>List of available parameters</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-legend.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the list of available parameters.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The available parameters</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
        <note>
          <para>
            That the <guilabel>Path</guilabel> and <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel>
            fields be separated is only a matter of making easier to set up the
            data.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you do not use, by example, the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button,
            you may perfectly enter the path of the command along with its parameters
            in any of the <guilabel>Path</guilabel> or <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel>
            entry boxes (but not in both), as long as you take care of separating them
            by at least one space.
          </para>
        </note>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-work">
        <title>Where the action should it be executed ?</title>
        <para>
          Your action may be executed in a particular working directory.
          You may specify it in the <guilabel>Command</guilabel> tab, in the
          <guilabel>Working directory</guilabel> entry box, or by clicking
          on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to select a folder on the 
          filesystem.
        </para>
        <para>
          The working directory defaults to <literal>%d</literal>, which runs
          the command in the base directory of the first selected item.
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-how">
        <title>How the action should it be executed ?</title>
        <figure id="nact-FIG-execution">
          <title>Configuration of the execution mode</title>
          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-execution-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
              </imageobject>
              <textobject>
                <phrase>Shows how to configure the execution mode of a command.</phrase>
              </textobject>
              <caption>
                <para>Configuration of the execution mode</para>
              </caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-mode">
          <title>Specifying the execution mode</title>
          <para>
            The execution mode of your command may be choosen between following 
            values:
          </para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Normal
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the command as a standard graphical user interface.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Terminal
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the preferred terminal of the desktop environment,
                  and runs the command in it.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Embedded
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Makes use of a special feature of the file manager which may allow
                  a terminal to be ran in it.
                </para>
                <para>
                  As &nautilus; does not have this feature, this option is strictly
                  equivalent to <literal>Terminal</literal> option.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Display output
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the preferred terminal of the desktop environment, and
                  runs the command in it. At end, standard streams (stdout, stderr) 
                  are collected and displayed.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
          <para>
            The execution mode of a command defaults to <literal>Normal</literal>.
            That is, the command is executed without any particular pre- or
            post-work.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-notify">
          <title>Specifying the startup notification</title>
          <para>
            If the execution mode of the command is actually <literal>Normal</literal>,
            and if you know that the application will send a <literal>remove</literal>
            message with the <envar>DESKTOP_STARTUP_ID</envar> environment variable set,
            then check the <guilabel>Startup notify</guilabel> checkbox.
          </para>
          <para>
            See the
            <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Standards/startup-notification-spec" type="http">
            <citetitle>Startup Notification Protocol Specification</citetitle></ulink>
            for more details.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-class">
          <title>Specifying the window class</title>
          <para>
            If the execution mode of the command is actually <literal>Normal</literal>,
            and if you know that the application will map at least one window with a
            given class name,
            then enter that name into the <guilabel>Startup Window Manager class</guilabel>
            entry box.
          </para>
          <para>
            See the
            <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Standards/startup-notification-spec" type="http">
            <citetitle>Startup Notification Protocol Specification</citetitle></ulink>
            for more details.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-user">
          <title>Specifying the owner of the execution</title>
          <para>
            Enter in the <guilabel>Execute as user</guilabel> entry box the username
            or the <acronym>UID</acronym> of the user your command must be ran as.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you do not enter anything in this field, then the command will be
            executed as the current user.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-singular">
          <title>Singular <abbrev>vs.</abbrev> plural forms</title>
          <para>
          </para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

    </sect2>
    <!-- end of creating an action -->

    <sect2 id="usage-organize-action">
      <title>Organizing actions in menus</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-edit">
      <title>Editing</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-save">
      <title>Saving</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-export">
      <title>Exporting</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-import">
      <title>Importing</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>
