<!-- ============================== Usage ============================= -->
<!-- Use this section to describe how to use the application to perform the
     tasks for which the application is designed. -->

  <sect1 id="usage">
    <title>Using &appname;</title>

    <sect2 id="usage-create-action">
      <title>Creating an action</title>
      <para>
        To create a new action, choose
        <menuchoice>
          <shortcut>
            <keycombo>
              <keycap>Ctrl</keycap>
              <keycap>N</keycap>
            </keycombo>
          </shortcut>
          <guimenu>File</guimenu>
          <guisubmenu>New action</guisubmenu>
        </menuchoice>.
      </para>
      <para>
        A new action is inserted in the items list. The exact place where the
        action is inserted depends of the current sort order of the items list:
      </para>
      <variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            Manual order:
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The new action is inserted just before the current action or menu.
            </para>
            <para>
              This place will not change when you later modify the label of the action.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>
            Ascending (resp. descending) alphabetical order:
          </term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
              The new action is inserted at the correct place, regarding the default
              &laquosp;<literal>New Nautilus action</literal>&spraquo; label.
            </para>
            <para>
              This place will be automatically changed, each time you modify the
              label of the action.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
      <para>
        Properties of this new action are also displayed in right tabs.
      </para>
      <note>
        <para>
          In theitems list, the new action is displayed in italic characters.
          Italics are used as a reminder that the item has not yet been saved.
        </para>
      </note>
      <note>
        <para>
          The new action is also displayed in red color in the items list.
          Red color is used as an indicator that the item
          is invalid, that is that the item cannot be candidate to be displayed in a
          &nautilus; context menu because some of its informations are missing or erroneous.
          Here, and though this newly inserted action has some suitable defaults, it lacks a 
          command to be executed to be considered valid by &appname;
        </para>
      </note>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-where">
        <title>Where should appear the action ?</title>
        <para>
          &nautilus; file-manager may display your custom action in different places,
          depending on you will request here, and if some item is currently selected.
        </para>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-selection">
          <title>Targeting the selection context menu</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in selection context menu</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; context menu, as long as at least one item is selected in 
            the file-manager. Your action will so deal with currently selected
            item(s).
          </para>
          <tip>
            <para>
              When an action targets the selection context menu, and is actually 
              displayed in &nautilus; context menu, then it is also displayed
              in the <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menu.
            </para>
          </tip>
          <para>
            This checkbox is activated by default.
          </para>
          <para>
            When targeting the selection context menu, and in order to be
            actually displayed, all the conditions defined in
            your candidate action must be met by each item currently selected
            in the &nautilus; file-manager. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-location">
          <title>Targeting the location context menu</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in location context menu</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; context menu, when the file-manager selection will be empty.
            Your action will so deal with currently displayed location.
          </para>
          <tip>
            <para>
              When an action targets the location context menu, and is actually 
              displayed in &nautilus; context menu, then it is also displayed
              in the <guimenu>File</guimenu> menu.
            </para>
          </tip>
          <para>
            When targeting the location context menu, and in order to be
            actually displayed, all the conditions defined in
            your candidate action must be met by the location currently displayed
            in the &nautilus; file-manager. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-toolbar">
          <title>Targeting the toolbar</title>
          <para>
            When <guilabel>Display item in the toolbar</guilabel> checkbox
            is activated, then your action will be candidate to be displayed in 
            &nautilus; toolbar.
          </para>
          <para>
            Actions displayed in the toolbar only deal with the location which
            is currently displayed in the file-manager, not with the items which
            may be currently selected (or not). In order to be displayed, all the
            conditions defined in your candidate action must so be met by the
            current location. 
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-where-notes">
          <title>Notes</title>
            <para>
              An action may target both the selection context menu, the location context
              menu and the toolbar, or one or more among these. If no target is defined,
              <abbrev>i.e.</abbrev> if the three checkboxes are unchecked, then your action
              will never be displayed.
            </para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-display">
        <title>How the action will it appear ?</title>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-display-menu">
          <title>If your action targets a menu</title>
          <para>
            Whether your action targets the selection context menu or the location
            context menu, and both in &nautilus; context menus that in 
            <guimenu>File</guimenu> or <guimenu>Edit</guimenu> menus, your
            action will be displayed as
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Context label</guilabel> as a label,
              </para>
              <para>
                The label is a mandatory property of your action. If it happens
                to be empty, then your action will be considered as invalid by
                &prodname;, and will never be candidate to be displayed in the
                file-manager context menus.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Icon</guilabel>,
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                associated with the <guilabel>Tooltip</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>
              Depending of the exact configuration of your desktop environment,
              the icon may or may not be displayed in front of the label in
              the menu.
            </para>
          </note>
          <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the label, the icon name of the tooltip.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
          </tip>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-display-toolbar">
          <title>If your action targets the toolbar</title>
          <para>
            In the toolbar, your action will be displayed as
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Toolbar label</guilabel> as a label,
              </para>
              <tip>
                <para>
                  The toolbar label defaults to the same label than
                  those used in menus. By unchecking the
                  <guilabel>Use same label for icon in the toolbar</guilabel>
                  checkbox, then you can define a label specific to the
                  toolbar, usually shorter those defined for the menus.
                </para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                the <guilabel>Icon</guilabel>,
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                associated with the <guilabel>Tooltip</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <note>
            <para>
              Depending of the exact configuration of your desktop environment,
              the toolbar label may or may not be displayed in front of the icon
              in the toolbar.
            </para>
          </note>
          <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the toolbar label, the icon name of the tooltip.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
          </tip>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-display-icon">
          <title>Choosing an icon</title>
          <para>
            You have two ways of choosing the icon associated to your action.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the dropdown list to select an icon among standard
                themed icons of your desktop environment.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button to search 
                for an image in the filesystem.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-when">
        <title>When the action will it be displayed ?</title>
        <para>
          Whether your action is actually displayed in &nautilus; file-manager
          context menus and toolbar depends of the conditions you will define
          for it.
        </para>
        <para>
          All defined conditions must be satisfied by the current file-manager
          selection (resp. location) in order your action be displayed. 
        </para>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-basenames">
          <title>Basenames</title>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-basenames">
            <title>Basename-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-basenames-tab.png" format="PNG" />
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define basename-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The basename-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            You may define that your action will only appear depending on the basenames
            of the items currently selected in the file-manager. You may define that each
            item of the selection must meet some sort of condition; and you may simultaneously
            decide that none of the selected item(s) can have some other sort of basename.
          </para>
          <para>
            Defining a new basename-based condition involves only two simple steps.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Press <keycap>Insert</keycap> or click on 
                <guibutton><inlinegraphic fileref="figures/add.png"/></guibutton>
                button to insert a new condition filter
              </para>
              <tip>
                <para>
                  A condition may use &laquosp;<literal>*</literal>&spraquo; or
                  &laquosp;<literal>?</literal>&spraquo; wildcard characters.
                </para>
              </tip>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guilabel>Must match one of</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>Must not match any of</guilabel> radio button in the same
                row to set a &laquosp;must have&spraquo; or
                &laquosp;must not have&spraquo; condition.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            Depending of your target operating system, make sure that the
            <guilabel>Match case</guilabel> checkbox is activated (or not). 
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                When activated, all filters are considered as case sensitive,
                which means that <filename>/my/file</filename> filename is
                considered distinct from <filename>My/File</filename> one.
              </para>
              <para>
                This is the default behavior on Unix-like systems.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                When disactivated, filters are considered as case insensitive,
                which means that <filename>/my/file</filename> and
                <filename>My/File</filename> filenames are considered the same
                name.
              </para>
              <para>
                This is most probably what you want if you target some sort of
                &windows; system.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            When the action is examined to see if it should be displayed, the basename
            of each currently selected item is compared to the list of these basename-based
            conditions for this action.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default, the basename-based condition is just one
            &laquosp;<literal>must match *</literal>&spraquo; condition.
            This means that basenames are not considered as a relevant condition
            for the action.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-mimetypes">
          <title>Mimetypes</title>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-mimetypes">
            <title>Mimetype-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-mimetypes-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define mimetype-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The mimetype-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            You may define that your action will only appear depending on the mimetypes
            of the items currently selected in the file-manager. You may define that each
            item of the selection must meet some sort of condition; and you may simultaneously
            decide that none of the selected item(s) can have some other sort of mimetype.
          </para>
          <para>
            Defining a new mimetype-based condition involves only two simple steps.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Press <keycap>Insert</keycap> or click on 
                <guibutton><inlinegraphic fileref="figures/add.png"/></guibutton>
                button to insert a new condition filter
              </para>
              <para>
                A mimetype must be defined as a <literal>group/subgroup</literal>
                group.
              </para>
              <para>
                Some sort of wildcards are accepted.
              </para>
              <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                  <para>
                    The &laquosp;<literal>*/*</literal>&spraquo; literal
                    matches all mimetypes. As a convenient shortcut, the
                    &laquosp;<literal>*</literal>&spraquo; literal is
                    also accepted for the same purpose.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                  <para>
                    A &laquosp;<literal>group/*</literal>&spraquo; string
                    matches all subgroups of <literal>group</literal> mimetype.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
              </itemizedlist>
              <note>
                <para>
                  The &laquosp;<literal>*/subgroup</literal>&spraquo; string
                  is not accepted as a valid wildcard.
                </para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guilabel>Must match one of</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>Must not match any of</guilabel> radio button in the same
                row to set a &laquosp;must have&spraquo; or
                &laquosp;must not have&spraquo; condition.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            When the action is examined to see if it should be displayed, the mimetype
            of each currently selected item is compared to the list of these mimetype-based
            conditions for this action.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default, the mimetype-based condition is just one
            &laquosp;<literal>must match */*</literal>&spraquo; condition.
            This means that mimetypes are not considered as a relevant condition
            for the action.
          </para>
          <example>
            <title>Example of usual mimetypes</title>
            <variablelist>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>
                  all/all
                </term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>
                    Matches all items.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>
                  all/allfiles
                </term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>
                    Matches all regular files.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
              <varlistentry>
                <term>
                  inode/directory
                </term>
                <listitem>
                  <para>
                    Matches only directories.
                  </para>
                </listitem>
              </varlistentry>
            </variablelist>
          </example>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-folders">
          <title>Folders</title>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-folders">
            <title>Folder-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-folders-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define folder-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The folder-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            You may define that your action will only appear depending on the directory
            the items currently selected in the file-manager are located in.
            You may define that each item of the selection must be located in one
            hierarchy or in another; and you may simultaneously
            decide that none of the selected item(s) can be located in some other
            hierarchy.
          </para>
          <para>
            Defining a new folder-based condition involves only two simple steps.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Press <keycap>Insert</keycap> or click on 
                <guibutton><inlinegraphic fileref="figures/add.png"/></guibutton>
                button to insert a new condition filter, or click on
                <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to select a folder on the filesystem.
              </para>
              <para>
                A folder-based condition must be understood as the specification
                of the hierarchy in which the currently examined item should (or
                should not) stay.
              </para>
              <note>
                <para>
                  The &laquosp;<literal>*</literal>&spraquo; and
                  &laquosp;<literal>?</literal>&spraquo; characters
                  are accepted as wildcards at any level of the defined
                  folder filter.
                </para>
              </note>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guilabel>Must match one of</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>Must not match any of</guilabel> radio button in the same
                row to set a &laquosp;must have&spraquo; or
                &laquosp;must not have&spraquo; condition.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            When the action is examined to see if it should be displayed, the location
            of each currently selected item is compared to the list of these folder-based
            conditions for this action.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default, the folder-based condition is just one
            &laquosp;<literal>must match /</literal>&spraquo; condition.
            As <literal>/</literal> is always the top of an Unix-like filesystem,
            then all selected files always match this condition.
          </para>
          <note>
            <para>
              If you target a &windows; system, then this default value may
              not be what you actually want.
            </para>
          </note>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-schemes">
          <title>Schemes</title>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-schemes">
            <title>Scheme-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-schemes-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define scheme-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The scheme-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            You may define that your action will only appear depending on the schemes
            of the URIs of the items currently selected in the file-manager.
            You may define that each item of the selection must have some scheme;
            and you may simultaneously
            decide that none of the selected item(s) may have some other scheme.
          </para>
          <para>
            Defining a new scheme-based condition involves only two simple steps.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Press <keycap>Insert</keycap> or click on 
                <guibutton><inlinegraphic fileref="figures/add.png"/></guibutton>
                button to insert a new condition filter, or click on
                <guibutton>Common</guibutton> to select a scheme among these
                defined as default schemes in 
                <menuchoice>
                  <guimenu>Edit</guimenu>
                  <guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
                </menuchoice>.
              </para>
              <para>
                Scheme-based conditions only accept
                &laquosp;<literal>*</literal>&spraquo; wildcard,
                which stands for &laquosp;any scheme&spraquo;.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guilabel>Must match one of</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>Must not match any of</guilabel> radio button in the same
                row to set a &laquosp;must have&spraquo; or
                &laquosp;must not have&spraquo; condition.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            When the action is examined to see if it should be displayed, the
            scheme of the URI
            of each currently selected item is compared to the list of these
            scheme-based conditions for this action.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default, the folder-based condition is just one
            &laquosp;<literal>must match *</literal>&spraquo; condition,
            which means that schemes are not relevant for this action.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-capabilities">
          <title>Capabilities</title>
          <para>
            Capabilities are some properties that a file may exhibit to the user.
          </para>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-add-capability">
            <title>Managed capabilities</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-new-capability.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the list of managed capabilities.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The list of managed capabilities</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            But the <literal>Local</literal> capability, all others are dependant
            of the user who executes the command.
          </para>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-capabilities">
            <title>Capability-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-capabilities-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define capability-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The capability-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
          <para>
            You may so decide that your action will appear, or not, depending
            on the capabilities of the selected item(s) <abbrev>vs.</abbrev>
            the current user.
          </para>
          <para>
            Defining a new capability-based condition involves only two simple steps.
          </para>
          <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Press <keycap>Insert</keycap> or click on 
                <guibutton><inlinegraphic fileref="figures/add.png"/></guibutton>
                button to insert a new condition filter.
              </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
              <para>
                Click on the <guilabel>Must match one of</guilabel> or
                <guilabel>Must not match any of</guilabel> radio button in the same
                row to set a &laquosp;must have&spraquo; or
                &laquosp;must not have&spraquo; condition.
              </para>
            </listitem>
          </itemizedlist>
          <para>
            When the action is examined to see if it should be displayed, this list
            of capabilities that selected item(s) must match (or not) is compared
            to those exhibited to the user.
          </para>
          <para>
            By default, the capability-based condition list is empty. This means
            that capabilities are not relevant for this action.
          </para>
          <note>
            <para>
              If you target a &windows; system, then this default value may
              not be what you actually want.
            </para>
          </note>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-when-environment">
          <title>Environment</title>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-tab-environment">
            <title>Environment-based conditions</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-environment-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the tab which lets you define environment-based conditions.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The environment-based conditions tab</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-count">
            <title>Selection count</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear if the current
              selection in the file-manager has some precise count.
            </para>
            <example>
              <title>A selection count use case</title>
              <para>
                If your action consists in displaying the difference between
                two files, you may define here
                <guilabel>Count = (equal to) 2</guilabel>.
              </para>
            </example>
            <para>
              To define a selection count condition
            </para>
            <itemizedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Select in the dropdown list the operator you want apply
                  to the selection count
                </para>
                <simplelist type="vert">
                  <member><literal>&lt; (strictly less than)</literal></member>
                  <member><literal>= (equal to)</literal></member>
                  <member><literal>&gt; (strictly greather than)</literal></member>
                </simplelist>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Enter the reference count you wish.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            <para>
              The selection count defaults to
              <guilabel>Count > (strictly greater than) 0</guilabel>
              which means that the action will be candidate to be displayed
              as soon as at least one item is selected in the file-manager.
            </para>
          </sect5>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-desktop">
            <title>Desktop environment</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear in some given
              desktop environments, or, contrarily, will not appear in some
              given desktop environments.
            </para>
            <para>
              To define the desktop environment condition
            </para>
            <orderedlist>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  First select the type of filter
                </para>
                <simplelist type="vert">
                  <member>does your action should always appear, regarding of
                   the desktop environment ?</member>
                  <member>does your action should also appear in some desktop
                   environment(s) ?</member>
                  <member>does your action should never appeat in some
                   desktop environment(s) ?</member>
                </simplelist>
              </listitem>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  If your action does not should always appear, then
                  select the relevant desktop environment(s) in the listbox
                  in the right side.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </orderedlist>
            <para>
              The target desktop environment condition defaults to
              <guilabel>Always appear</guilabel>
              which means that the action will be candidate to be displayed
              regarding of the current desktop environment.
            </para>
          </sect5>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-executable">
            <title>Presence of an executable</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear in some given
              file is present on the filesystem and is executable.
            </para>
            <para>
              To define the relevant file, enter its full filename in the
              <guilabel>Appears if the file is executable</guilabel> entry
              box, or click on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to select a file
              on the filesystem.
            </para>
            <para>
              Leave the field empty if this condition is not relevant for
              your action.
            </para>
            <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the searched filename or its options.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
            </tip>
          </sect5>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-dbus">
            <title>D-Bus-registered name</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear in some given
              name is registered on D-Bus system at runtime.
            </para>
            <para>
              To define the relevant name, enter it in the
              <guilabel>Appears if the name is registered on D-Bus</guilabel>
              entry box.
            </para>
            <para>
              Leave the field empty if this condition is not relevant for
              your action.
            </para>
            <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the searched name.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
            </tip>
          </sect5>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-true">
            <title>Customized condition</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear in some given
              command outputs a <literal>true</literal> string.
            </para>
            <para>
              This lets you define your own customized condition filter,
              by writing a small script which outputs, or not, the
              <literal>true</literal> string when it is ran.
            </para>
            <para>
              To define the command, enter it in the
              <guilabel>Appears if the command outputs "true"</guilabel>
              entry box.
            </para>
            <para>
              Leave the field empty if this condition is not relevant for
              your action.
            </para>
            <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the executed filename or its options.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
            </tip>
          </sect5>

          <sect5 id="usage-create-action-when-environment-run">
            <title>Running process</title>
            <para>
              You may define that your action will only appear in some given
              binary is currently running.
            </para>
            <para>
              To define the binary, enter its name in the
              <guilabel>Appears if the binary is running</guilabel>
              entry box, or click on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to select
              a file on the filesystem.
            </para>
            <note>
              <para>
                Even if you enter here the full filename of a binary, only
                its basename will be searched for in the processes list
                at runtime.
              </para>
            </note>
            <para>
              Leave the field empty if this condition is not relevant for
              your action.
            </para>
            <tip>
              <para>
                You may embed some parameters in the searched name.
                These parameters will be dynamically substituted at runtime with values
                which will depend of currently selected item(s). 
              </para>
            </tip>
          </sect5>
        </sect4>

      </sect3>
      <!-- end of sect3 - conditions section -->

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-what">
        <title>What the action should it execute ?</title>
        <para>
          You most probably want your action eventually ends up with
          executing something. As a matter of fact, having something
          to execute is one of the few conditions which are required
          in order an action be considered as valid.
        </para>
        <para>
          Enter the command you wish to execute in the <guilabel>Path</guilabel>
          entry box. Or click on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to
          select a file on the filesystem.
        </para>
        <para>
          Enter the parameters of your command in the
          <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel> entry box.
        </para>
        <para>
          The <guibutton>Legend</guibutton> button has a toggling action:
          click once to display the <guilabel>Parameter Legend</guilabel>
          dialog box; click a second time to hide it.
        </para>
          <figure id="nact-FIG-legend">
            <title>List of available parameters</title>
            <screenshot>
              <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                  <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-legend.png" format="PNG"/>
                </imageobject>
                <textobject>
                  <phrase>Shows the list of available parameters.</phrase>
                </textobject>
                <caption>
                  <para>The available parameters</para>
                </caption>
              </mediaobject>
            </screenshot>
          </figure>
        <note>
          <para>
            That the <guilabel>Path</guilabel> and <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel>
            fields be separated is only a matter of making easier to set up the
            data.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you do not use, by example, the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button,
            you may perfectly enter the path of the command along with its parameters
            in any of the <guilabel>Path</guilabel> or <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel>
            entry boxes (but not in both), as long as you take care of separating them
            by at least one space.
          </para>
        </note>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-work">
        <title>Where the action should it be executed ?</title>
        <para>
          Your action may be executed in a particular working directory.
          You may specify it in the <guilabel>Command</guilabel> tab, in the
          <guilabel>Working directory</guilabel> entry box, or by clicking
          on <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> to select a folder on the 
          filesystem.
        </para>
        <para>
          The working directory defaults to <literal>%d</literal>, which runs
          the command in the base directory of the first selected item.
        </para>
      </sect3>

      <sect3 id="usage-create-action-how">
        <title>How the action should it be executed ?</title>
        <figure id="nact-FIG-execution">
          <title>Configuration of the execution mode</title>
          <screenshot>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="figures/nact-execution-tab.png" format="PNG"/>
              </imageobject>
              <textobject>
                <phrase>Shows how to configure the execution mode of a command.</phrase>
              </textobject>
              <caption>
                <para>Configuration of the execution mode</para>
              </caption>
            </mediaobject>
          </screenshot>
        </figure>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-mode">
          <title>Specifying the execution mode</title>
          <para>
            The execution mode of your command may be choosen between following 
            values:
          </para>
          <variablelist>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Normal
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the command as a standard graphical user interface.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Terminal
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the preferred terminal of the desktop environment,
                  and runs the command in it.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Embedded
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Makes use of a special feature of the file manager which may allow
                  a terminal to be ran in it.
                </para>
                <para>
                  As &nautilus; does not have this feature, this option is strictly
                  equivalent to <literal>Terminal</literal> option.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            <varlistentry>
              <term>
                Display output
              </term>
              <listitem>
                <para>
                  Starts the preferred terminal of the desktop environment, and
                  runs the command in it. At end, standard streams (stdout, stderr) 
                  are collected and displayed.
                </para>
              </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
          </variablelist>
          <para>
            The execution mode of a command defaults to <literal>Normal</literal>.
            That is, the command is executed without any particular pre- or
            post-work.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-notify">
          <title>Specifying the startup notification</title>
          <para>
            If the execution mode of the command is actually <literal>Normal</literal>,
            and if you know that the application will send a <literal>remove</literal>
            message with the <envar>DESKTOP_STARTUP_ID</envar> environment variable set,
            then check the <guilabel>Startup notify</guilabel> checkbox.
          </para>
          <para>
            See the
            <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Standards/startup-notification-spec" type="http">
            <citetitle>Startup Notification Protocol Specification</citetitle></ulink>
            for more details.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-class">
          <title>Specifying the window class</title>
          <para>
            If the execution mode of the command is actually <literal>Normal</literal>,
            and if you know that the application will map at least one window with a
            given class name,
            then enter that name into the <guilabel>Startup Window Manager class</guilabel>
            entry box.
          </para>
          <para>
            See the
            <ulink url="http://www.freedesktop.org/Standards/startup-notification-spec" type="http">
            <citetitle>Startup Notification Protocol Specification</citetitle></ulink>
            for more details.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-user">
          <title>Specifying the owner of the execution</title>
          <para>
            Enter in the <guilabel>Execute as user</guilabel> entry box the username
            or the <acronym>UID</acronym> of the user your command must be ran as.
          </para>
          <para>
            If you do not enter anything in this field, then the command will be
            executed as the current user.
          </para>
        </sect4>

        <sect4 id="usage-create-action-how-singular">
          <title>Singular <abbrev>vs.</abbrev> plural forms</title>
          <para>
          </para>
        </sect4>
      </sect3>

    </sect2>
    <!-- end of creating an action -->

    <sect2 id="usage-organize-action">
      <title>Organizing actions in menus</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-profile">
      <title>Defining more profiles</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-edit">
      <title>Editing</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-save">
      <title>Saving</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-export">
      <title>Exporting</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

    <sect2 id="usage-import">
      <title>Importing</title>
      <para>
      </para>
    </sect2>

  </sect1>
  <!-- end of sect1 - using nautils-actions-config-tool -->
